# Dan Snow

Mob: +44 (0) 7490 212424 Email: Daniel.snow@nuffield.ox.ac.uk Nuffield College, Oxford, OX1 1NF

I am a political sociologist at the University of Oxford interested in elections, attitudes, and more specifically campaign and media effects. My research is exclusively quantitative methods based.

## Education

## Nuffield College, Oxford University: 2019 - Present

- Currently a DPhil candidate in the Department of Sociology, focussed on the politics of Brexit
  and its aftermath
- Funded by the ESRC (full tuition plus £15,300 per annum for three years) on an Advanced Quantitative Methods scholarship

### St Cross College, Oxford University: 2018 - 2019

- Distinction received in MSc in Sociology
- Received a distinction in all subcomponents, including two papers for Political Sociology and Advanced Quantitative Methods
- Received a mark of 75 (distinction) for my 10,000 word thesis: 'Project Fear: Assessing the importance of campaign contact and economic expectations in the 2016 EU referendum' this was the second highest mark for my cohort

### Merton College, Oxford University: 2015 - 2018

- 1st Class Degree in Philosophy, Politics and Economics
- Also achieved a 1st in Prelims exams at end of first year; ranked 3rd in year group for Philosophy and 13th for PPE

### Prince William School, Oundle: 2009 - 2014

- A Levels: A\* in History, A in Maths, A in Physics
- GCSE: 10 A\*s (inc. English and Maths), A\* distinction in Further Maths

### **Academic Awards and Achievements**

- Sam McNaughton Prize for Philosophy, (only awarded to one student in Merton College per year)
- 1st place out of 29 entrants in Merton College essay competition for a Politics tutorial essay discussing changes to class voting in Britain since 1950
- Shortlisted for Q-step Essay Prize for data analysis essay, (out of all first year Politics students)
- Received Exhibitioner Scholarship in 2nd year of undergraduate studies for academic success,
   and Postmaster scholarship in 3rd year for continued excellence

# Research Experience

Updated election-forecast MRP model for a polling company: Dec 2019

- Built from scratch a statistical model (in R) to update a prior forecast as the Exit Poll and real results became public
- Delivered updates throughout election night to a client

Co-authored Blog Post with Prof. Steve Fisher: Nov-Dec 2019

- Collected data for an analysis of differences in polling estimates in the run-up to the 2019
   UK General Election
- Helped in both the analysis and the write-up of the results

Research Assistant to on CSI Brexit Project: Aug-Sept 2019

- Wrote the CSI Brexit 7 research note and helped edit the accompanying blog post written by Prof. Anthony Heath
- Provided ideas for questions on the wave 8 survey which were then adapted and included by Prof. Heath and Dr. Lindsay Richards

# Teaching Experience

Quantitative Methods Tutor (Oxford University DPIR): 2019 to present

- Taught 7 weeks of quantitative methods (theory and practice in R) to second-year undergraduates taking Politics modules
- Classes had c.10-20 students and required lecturing and practical coding help
- Helped to develop course materials and wrote the take-home exam

PPE Tutor for the UNIQ course (Oxford University): Summer 2019

- Gave three 1-hour tutorials to groups of two or three potential PPE applicants taking part on Oxford's UNIQ program
- Provided verbal feedback on the students' essays and then facilitated discussion and pushed the students' ideas and thinking

#### Graduate Mentor: 2018 to present

- Offer guidance to current Merton PPE students, either with general topics like revision strategies or more focused subject-specific questions
- Marked first-year Politics tutorial essays and collections (college exams) provided in-depth feedback and points for improvement

### Other Relevant Skills

- Proficient in R and STATA for basic statistical analysis and presentation of findings
- Highly proficient in LATEX and RMarkdown
- Basic knowledge of web-design with HTML and CSS
- Basic knowledge of Python

# Non-Academic Experience

#### Internship - Oxbow Partners: Summers of 2018 and 2019 (11 Weeks Total)

- Interned at Oxbow Partners, a boutique strategy consultancy, and was invited to work a second summer there
- Wrote a 23-page report on InsurTech innovation in the Life, Pensions & Wealth sector that was distributed to industry leaders
- Regularly participated in project meetings with Oxbow managers and partners, and majorly contributed to two consulting projects
- Contributed content for the firms blog, (readership c.2000 industry professionals)

### Oundle School Sports Centre: 2013 - 2014

- Started as Recreational Assistant and was promoted to part-time Duty Manager in 2014 after being recommended to management by colleagues
- Responsible for managing the sports centre and its staff, and for ensuring customer safety
- Required to make executive decisions and lead a team of up to 5 recreational assistants
- Organised/supervised group events for up to 100 people; responsible for safety of attendees